Latest résumé always available at http://forsetti.com, best viewed with Google Chrome.

Skills & Qualifications

- Strong problem solving skills, able to decompose complex problems and match technology to requirements.
- Able to identify and develop methods of integration across heterogeneous technologies.
- Strong interpersonal skills, able to interact in a team environment, as a leader or member.
- Strong advocate for Open Standards and Free/Open/Community Source Software.
- Twelve years experience at the University of Connecticut developing, leading, and providing
 enterprise scale solutions to 50,000 immediate customers in multiple locations around the
 state of Connecticut, and to a public community located around the world.
- Four years supervisory experience with oversight of teams supporting over three hundred Linux, VMW are, Windows, Unix, and Mainframe servers and services.
- Co-maintainer of mod_auth_cas, the official Jasig CAS Apache module, included in Debian, Ubuntu, and Fedora Linux distributions.
- Proficient in numerous technology areas, including (but not limited to):
 Linux
 - Administration of Debian Linux, Ubuntu Linux, SuSE Linux Enterprise Server, Red Hat Enterprise Linux.
 - Administration of Apache, Tomcat, OpenLDAP, MIT Kerberos, Samba, OpenAFS, Subversion, Plone, Trac, Zabbix, and other enterprise services commonly deployed on Linux.

Virtualization & "Cloud"

- Strategy and oversight of VMWare ESX, Red Hat Enteprise Virtualization, & IBM Blade Center deployments providing "Private Cloud" solution.
- Familiarity with several "Private Cloud" and "Public Cloud" solutions, including Red Hat Enterprise Virtualization. IBM System z. Amazon EC2. Google Apps. Microsoft Azure.

Identity & Access Management Middleware

- Administration of MIT Kerberos, OpenLDAP, Jasig CAS, Internet2 Shibboleth.
- Well versed in the functional areas of Identity & Access Management, including Identity Reconciliation and Provisioning, Levels of Assurance, Federated Authorization, Single Sign On, Identity Lifecycles, etc.

Microsoft

- Administration of Active Directory, WINS, DNS, File Services, and business applications on Windows 200x.
- Development in Python, Perl, Java, and C to integrate Microsoft environment with upstream identity and authentication systems.

Software Development

- Experience developing software in C, Java, Perl, PHP, Python, Visual C++.
- Limited experience developing web interfaces in XHTML, CSS, JavaScript.

Career

 September 2010 - Present: Lead of Linux & Virtualization Team, University of Connecticut ITS, Storrs CT

Proposed and was given leadership of a newly created 10-member Linux team in September 2010, consolidated from the previous Virtualization, Middleware, and R&D teams, plus the Linux members of the previous Unix team. Responsible for oversight and implementation of critical Linux-based strategies. Team is responsible for:

- Physical and virtual hosting on IBM Blade Centers and VMW are VSphere 5.
- Several hundred Debian, Red Hat, SuSE, and Ubuntu Linux installations.
- Web site and application hosting for individuals, departments, and the enterprise using Apache, PHP, Tomcat, Glassfish, and MySQL, serving two million requests/day.
- Authentication, authorization, and user provisioning technologies in support of access into University services, leveraging MIT Kerberos, OpenLDAP, Jasig CAS, and several

- thousand lines of locally developed C, Java, Perl, and Python.
- Mail infrastructure including Cyrus IMAP, Squirrelmail, Sendmail, Postfix, Barracuda Spam appliances, and locally developed alias management application, providing 35,000 mailboxes and filtering/routing one million emails/day, and implementation of new Google Apps for Education service for students, including negotiation of contract and development of migration process.
- Hosting of other University services, such as the Enterprise Learning Management Blackboard solution, the Open Source Kuali Financials ERP, CA Unicenter Service Desk, and dozens of academic and administrative services.

Also engaged in several new strategic endeavors, including:

- Expansion of the virtualization solution to a "Private Cloud".
- Improved manageability of Linux installations through consolidation of all Linux platforms to Red Hat Enterpise Linux, deployment of Zabbix and Red Hat Satellite Server for management and monitoring, and leveraging of Kickstart/PXE for rapid provisioning of new servers.
- Advancement of the current web hosting platform through development of Java and PHP platform standards, more effective use of the internal Private Cloud solution, stronger application and site isolation, and improved high-availability.
- Expansion of the current Identity and Access Management environment to provide federated authorization with Shibboleth and membership in the InCommon Federation.
- Introduction of new storage service, including acquisition and deployment of 1/2 petabyte NAS solution, and development of cost and sevice model to make available to University researchers.
- July 2009 August 2010: Interim Architect and Manager of Server Support
 Due to organizational changes, was asked to temporarily fill a functional management
 position. Accepted interim position with stipulation that responsibilities would be temporary,
 with rapid return to strategic/technical role. Provided management leadership to the three
 existing highly-functional teams and three new teams totaling 25 members.
 - Unix Team, hosting the University's PeopleSoft and Oracle solution on AIX, the Blackboard ELM solution on Solaris, and a variety of services such as DNS, web hosting, application hosting, podcasting, and email routing and filtering on Linux.
 - Mainframe Team, maintaining IBM T16 and z890 Mainframes, running MVS(zOS)/VM and all Mainframe security, printing, scheduling, backups, and software management, and providing zVM virtual hosting of several dozen Linux guests.
 - Windows Team, maintaining over one hundred Windows Server installations, and a variety
 of services such as as Active Directory, Exchange, file services, document management
 services, and numerous departmental services.
 - Virtualization Team, a newly formed team responsible for the new VMWare and IBM Blade Center environment, providing physical and virtual hosting for the Windows and Linux teams.
 - Middleware Team, a newly formed team responsible for "Application Middleware" including Tomcat and Glassfish application servers, and "Identity and Access Management Middleware" including OpenLDAP directories, MIT Kerberos, and CAS Web Initial Sign-On solutions.
 - R&D Team, a newly formed team responsible for researching future technologies and developing innovative solutions to immediate needs, often integrating third-party software with existing infrastructure.

Also led or oversaw major consolidation initiatives:

- Deployment of two IBM Blade Center H solutions and VMWare VSphere 4.0 hosting over 100 Windows and Linux servers, to replace two legacy VMWare installations and decommission several dozen physical Linux and Windows servers.
- Deployment of SpringSource to Server solution to consolidate legacy Glassfish servers and several dozen unmanaged Tomcat installations of various versions.
- Development of strategy to consolidate variety of unmanaged Red Hat, SuSE, Ubuntu, and Debian installations to a Red Hat Enterprise Linux and Debian Linux.
- Deployment of an IBM z10 mainframe to consolidate all mainframe workloads from legacy

T16 and z890 systems, reducing risk of legacy hardware and reducing heat/power requirements in data center.

September 2008 - April 2009: Team Lead for Windows Server Team
 Led team of 7 responsible for all aspects of 100+ Microsoft Windows servers, including maintaining the University's central Active Directory and Exchange services, file services,

document management services, and several dozen departmental services.

- 2001 Present: Identity & Access Management Architect
 Responsible for developing strategy for expansion of Identity & Access Management solution
 and maintaining current solution including MIT Kerberos, OpenLDAP, Jasig CAS, and several
 locally developed provisioning solutions in C, Java, Perl, and Python.
- 2006 Present: Web Initial Sign-On Administrator
 Deployed UConn's first Web Initial Sign-On solution, Jasig CAS. Contributed the
 "JAASAuthenticationHandler" to meet local requirement for multiple authentication sources.
 Co-maintainer of mod auth cas, the official Jasig CAS Apache module.
- 2001 Present: Directory Services Administrator
 Designed and deployed the University's first-generation iPlanet LDAP and MIT Kerberos in
 2001 and second-generation OpenLDAP services in 2003. Developed provisioning solution in
 Perl and Java to manage user entries in LDAP and Kerberos.
- 2000 April 2009: Windows Server Team, Active Directory Administrator
 Joined Windows Server Support team in 2000, providing support for Windows and Novell
 servers distributed around campus. Co-designed UConn Active Directory in 2000 and
 developed provisioning solution in Perl to manage user entries and groups.

Other Notable Activities

- 2012: Member of "Real World Perspectives Panel: Virtualization" panel, presenting at Red Hat Summit 2012.
- 2011-2012: Co-chair of "State of Connecticut Joint Labor & Management IT Cost Savings and Transformation Working Group", charged with identifying potential savings and positive change in the use of IT throughout Connecticut State Agencies and Institutions.
- 2010: Success Story published by Mainline Information Systems "The University of Connecticut Virtualizes and Consolidates Storrs Data Center" (http://mainline.com/ web/pdfs/success-stories/SS-UnivConnecticut-Blade.pdf).
- 2010: Member of State of Connecticut "S6: Information Systems Records" committee, charged with updating state policy on IT records retention.
- 2009-2012: Chair of University of Connecticut Technology Implementers Group and Student Technology Advisory Group.
- 2007-2008: Member of Jasig Planning Committee as CAS Liaison for April 2008 conference in St. Paul titled "The Community Source Way".
- 2004-2008: Multiple presentations to the UConn LUG/ACM on a variety of technical topics.
- 2003-Present: Attend Internet2/EDUCAUSE Middleware-related conferences roughly bi-yearly.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Engineering, Computer Science and Engineering, University of Connecticut, 2000

- Graduated Magna Cum Laude, with a 3.6 final GPA.
- Top graduate in the School of Computer Science and Engineering.
- Course work included Software Engineering, Digital Design, Algorithmic Complexity, Network Theory, Parallel Computing, Compiler Theory, Database Theory, and Artificial Intelligence.